# **Benjamin Cato**

With over a decade of experience in **front-end development**, I thrive on infusing projects with creativity and passion. I excel in collaborative environments and approach each project as a work of art, taking pride in my role as the artist.

402 Bridgepoint Ln.
Woodstock, GA 30189
(404) 374-1696
bcato3000@gmail.com
bcato3000.github.io/portfolio

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Whereoware, Atlanta — Senior front-end developer

May 2023 - October 2023

Expertise in creating modular components via React and Storybook (via TypeScript)  $\cdot$  optimizing user interfaces for Optimizely (CMS)  $\cdot$  involved with front-end code review of PRs  $\cdot$  expertise in responsive web development and pixel-perfect UI  $\cdot$  team lead for multiple front-end projects  $\cdot$  composition breakdown of components  $\cdot$  AA SEO optimization  $\cdot$  mentor of junior front-end devs  $\cdot$  collaboration with back-end developers for optimal data structure and CMS integration

#### BrainJocks / Perficient, Alpharetta — Lead front-end developer

April 2013 - July 2020 / December 2021 - May 2023

Created SPAs via React for large-scale CMS platforms (Sitecore / Optimizely) · modular components and applications via React and Storybook (via TypeScript) · responsive web development expertise · AA & AAA SEO optimization · meticulous UI perfection · team lead for a variety of enterprise projects and component library · HTML5 / CSS3 / Sass / LESS and JS · design liaison · UI instructor of SCORE (our customized front-end software) · mentor of junior front-end devs · engaged in projects from inception to final production phase

## Fleetcor, Atlanta — Senior front-end developer

August 2020 - December 2021

Front-end development fintech  $\cdot$  collaborated with UI / UX designers and bridged the gap between graphical representations and technical implementation via vanilla JS, D3 Js for graphical interface  $\cdot$  front-end code review of PRs  $\cdot$  creator of global component library for enterprise purposes  $\cdot$  provided front-end expertise for HTML / CSS / JS  $\cdot$  unit-tests via Jest

#### **EDUCATION**

**The Creative Circus**, Atlanta — *Interactive Development* 

Graduate: 2012 - 2013

**Chattahoochee Tech,** Acworth — Computer Science

Graduate 2001 - 2003

 ${\bf Kennesaw\ State\ University,\ Kennesaw\ -\ Computer\ Science}$ 

**SKILLS** 

HTML5

CSS<sub>3</sub>

Sass

JavaScript

TypeScript

Storybook

**RESTful APIs** 

SPAs (React/Vue)

Node

Web components

Responsive design/dev

Cross-browser

Accessibility standards

Git

UX

Adobe creative suite

Figma

Agile / Scrum

Client-facing contributor

PC Windows

Mac iOS